http://www.alcaminow.com/privacypolicy

Our Commitment to Privacy
Alcami Corporation and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “Alcami”) are committed to respecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) describes how we collect, use, disclose, store and otherwise process information through www.alcaminow.com and affiliated websites, Alcami OnDemand, and other online products and services. In addition, this policy states how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. Information about Alcami’s customers is an important part of our business, and we are not in the business of selling it to others. We share customer information only as described below.
Alcami complies with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as set forth by the European Parliament. GDPR mandates that Alcami protect the personal data and privacy of EU data subjects. If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Policy and GDPR, the GDPR principles shall govern.
Scope
This Privacy Policy applies to personal information and other information collected by Alcami or its service providers from or about: (i) visitors to, or users of, its websites; (ii) prospective and current customers using Alcami hosting and information technology services; (iii) users of any mobile-device applications that it offers (such as its iOS and Android applications); (iv) service providers and business partners; (v) job applicants; and (vi) other third-parties that Alcami interacts with.
Collection of Information
Alcami collects personal information about you in connection with our services. Personal information refers to any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, such as an identification number, physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural, or social identifiers. Alcami collects personally identifiable information such as name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address only when you voluntarily submit it to us. When working with our company, you may be prompted to make an account, which may hold personal information such as your name, mailing address, email address, or contact information. We will use this information to respond to requests for information and may use this information to contact you. Prior to collecting this information, Alcami will obtain your consent. At any point in time, you can revoke consent and we will cease using and processing your data immediately.
Alcami may also collect Technical Information about you when you visit our websites, which your web browser automatically sends whenever you visit a website on the Internet. "Technical Information" is information that does not, by itself, identify a specific individual but which could be used to indirectly identify you. Our servers automatically record this information, which may include your Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser language, and the date and time of your request. This information remains in aggregate form and is used to understand how our visitors use our websites, so that we can make them better. We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers, and for purposes of system administration. We may share this type of information with our agents, business partners, consultants or other outside companies.
The use of cookies is now industry standard, and you will find them used by most major web sites. We use cookies in our marketing emails so that we can track your interaction with those messages, such as when you open the email or click a URL link that’s embedded within them. When recipients click on one of those URLs, they pass through a separate web server before arriving at the destination page on a company website. We use tools like pixel tags and cookies so that we can determine interest in particular topics and measure and improve the effectiveness of our communications. You are always free to decline the use of cookies, and you may still use the site; however, some parts of the site may not work properly for you.
When you download or use our mobile-device applications, or access one of our mobile-optimized websites, we may receive information about your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device.
Our websites include social media features and other widgets that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the organization providing it. Alcami may also collect information about you from other sources to help us correct or supplement our records, improve the quality or personalization of our services to you, and prevent or detect fraud.
Use of Personal Information
Alcami uses your personal information to provide you with products and services, such as to fulfill your requests for products, communicate with you about your requests, or to help us personalize our service offerings, websites, mobile services and advertising. We also use your personal information to protect the security and integrity of our websites, mobile services, and business functions. To do this, we combine personal and non-personal information, collected online and offline, including information from third-party sources.
Alcami uses your contact information to recommend products and services that might be of interest to you, in order to send you marketing and advertising messages such as newsletters, announcements, or to notify you about our upcoming events; for industry benchmarking and analysis consistent with our legitimate business purpose.
Employment Applications
In connection with a job application or inquiry, you may provide us with data about yourself, including your educational background and other personal information where required or permitted by law. We may use this information throughout Alcami and its joint ventures for the purpose of employment consideration.
Data of Minors
We do not knowingly collect any personal information from anyone under the age of 18, nor do we knowingly market our web sites to anyone under the age of 18.
Third-Party Vendors; Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties
In order to provide the services and improve Alcami’s website, we may engage the services of third-party vendors. In the process of supplying services to Alcami, these third-party vendors may need to collect personal information about you.
Alcami will not rent or sell your personal information to others but may disclose personal information with third-party vendors and service providers that work with Alcami. We will only share personal information with these vendors and service providers to help us provide a product or service to you.
Disclosure of Personal Information for Legal and Safety Reasons
Alcami may be required to disclose personal information to the authorities, law enforcement agencies, government agencies, or legal entities. We may disclose information by law, litigation, or as a matter of national security to comply with valid legal process. We may also need to disclose personal information in the event of an emergency that threatens an individual's life, health, or security.
Disclosure of Personal Information for Business Purposes
If Alcami sells any part of its business operations, Alcami may transfer personal information in connection with the sale. Prior to a sale occurring, Alcami will contact you to gain your consent for the disclosure of your personal information.
Links to Third-Party Websites, Services, and Applications
As a convenience to you, Alcami may provide links from this web site to other web sites maintained by independent third parties. This Privacy Policy applies solely to the information collected on this web site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave this site and to read the privacy policies of any web site that you may visit.
Onward Transfer Liability
In cases of onward transfer to third parties of your personal data, Alcami is potentially liable. In particular, Alcami remains responsible and liable under GDPR if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with its principles, unless Alcami proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.
Security Measures Taken to Protect Personal Information by Alcami
Security of all information is of the utmost importance for Alcami. Alcami uses technical and physical safeguards to protect the security of your personal information from unauthorized disclosure. Please be advised that although we take measures to create a secure and reliable site for you, such security measures cannot prevent all loss, misuse or alteration of personal information and to the fullest extent permitted by law, we are not responsible for any damages or liabilities relating to any such incidents. In the case of a data breach, we will notify you without delay of any loss, misuse or alteration of personal information that may affect you. We will notify relevant regulatory bodies within seventy-two (72) hours of a breach.
Data Retention and Storage
Alcami retains your information for business purposes, for as long as your account is active, and/or as long as is reasonably necessary to provide you with our products and services. Alcami will also retain your information as reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. We may also retain cached or archived copies of your information for a reasonable period of time. At any point in time, you can withdraw consent and we will immediately stop processing your data.
International Transfer of Personal Information
Alcami may share customer information within our family of companies for a variety of purposes, for example to provide you with the latest information about our products and services. To facilitate our global operations, Alcami may transfer personal data from your home country to other Alcami locations around the world. To protect your personal information, we will only transfer data to countries which provide an "adequate" level of personal data protection. If the data is transferred to countries without 'adequate' protection as determined by the European Parliament, we will use additional safeguards to ensure your data is protected.
Inquiry, Complaint, and Dispute Process
Alcami commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection/use of your personal information. If you have an inquiry or complaint regarding this Privacy Policy or the use or processing by Alcami of your data, you should first contact Alcami at (800) 575-4224 or through e-mail at Privacy@alcaminow.com. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.alcaminow.com for more information.
Changes to the Data Privacy Policy
Alcami may change this statement from time to time so please revisit this Privacy Policy periodically to be sure that you are familiar with our current policies. In the case of material changes that may adversely affect you, Alcami may provide a more direct way of notifying you of changes to this Privacy Policy.
Access Contact Point to Update/Delete Personal Information
You have the right to access and limit the use and disclosure of your personal data. If you would like to express your point of view, challenge an explanation of data use, or otherwise obtain further information, contact Privacy@alcaminow.com. If at any time after registering for information, your personal information changes, notify us and we will update your contact information. Please note, at any time, if you desire to obtain or transfer your information, we will provide you with your personal data in a structured and commonly used electronic format.
Location of Data Processing/StorageAny personal information collected about EU data subjects via our website is processed in the United States by Alcami or by a third party acting on our behalf. When you provide personal information to Alcami, you consent to the processing of your information in the United States. Our websites are hosted in the United States.
Applicable Regulations (California Privacy Rights)
California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits users of our website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to Privacy@alcaminow.com.
Choices About the Collection and Use of Your Information
In addition to the specific rights set forth below, Alcami gives you choices about the ways we collect, use, and share your personal information. You can choose what information will be stored and your preferences. However, if you choose not to provide certain details, some of your experiences with us may be affected. If at any point in time you wish to know what data we process about you, you can request to access the information by contacting Privacy@alcaminow.com.
Right of Access
At any point in time, you can confirm your data is being processed and request to access your data. If you wish to access/confirm your data is being processed, please contact Privacy@alcaminow.com.
Right to ConsentBefore collecting and using your personal data, Alcami will obtain consent. At any point in time, you can revoke consent and Alcami will stop using and processing your personal data.
Right to ErasureYou have the right to request that Alcami erase all of your personal data on a number of grounds, including if the data is no longer necessary for its original purpose or if you withdraw consent. If Alcami receives a request, we will inform all third parties who have the data of this request. For additional information on when you can request data erasure, please contact Privacy@alcaminow.com.
Right to Rectification
If any personal data is inaccurate or incomplete, you can request for Alcami to correct the data. When this occurs, Alcami will notify third parties who have access to the data of the requested change. If you wish to alter your data, please contact Privacy@alcaminow.com.
Right to Restrict ProcessingEven if personal data is still stored, now or in the future, you can request Alcami to stop using or processing your data. If you wish to restrict data processing, please contact Privacy@alcaminow.com.
Right to Object
You have the right to object to your personal data being processed for profiling, direct marketing, scientific research, and statistics. If you wish to object, please contact Privacy@alcaminow.com.
Rights Related to Automatic Decision Making and Profiling
At any point in time, you can contact an Alcami representative to express your point of view, challenge an explanation of data use, or otherwise obtain further information on automatic data processing.
Right to Data Portability
You have the right to transfer your personal data from one electronic processing system to another without being prevented from doing so by Alcami's data processor.
Contact Us
We welcome your questions and comments regarding this Privacy Policy and the use of your personal information. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or about our use of information, please contact us at (800) 575-4224 or at Privacy@alcaminow.com.
Last updated November 2020
© Copyright 2020 Alcami.   All rights reserved. Privacy Policy | Online Terms of Use
